Rohboam Amin

rohbam.99@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rohboam-amin

+447576-123322

Personal Statement:

An enthusiastic Computer Science graduate with expertise in multiple technologies. With a well-rounded academic history and working knowledge of technologies ranging from web, artificial intelligence, databases, and cloud computing. Having a rounded tech skill set and a deep passion for technology. Always striving towards making my presence an asset and to always leave a positive impact within any IT department.

Technical skills:

Programming: C/C++, Python, Java, C#, JavaScript, Swift

Analytics: SQL, MongoDB, Excel

Web/Media: HTML/CSS, WordPress, PHP, React, Davinci Resolve

Additional Tools: Hadoop, Docker, Odoo, Jenkins, AWS, Apache Spark

Key Skills, Certifications and Achievements:

Machine Learning Certification: SimpliLearn MATLAB Fundamentals on Ramp: MATLAB Official Silver Medals (Bachelors): Fall 2021 & Spring 2022

Education:

MSc Computer Science with Industrial Placement: University of East London January 2023- Present

Dissertation: Real-Time Forecasting of Bitcoin Price through Financial News Analysis Analysing financial news to extract sentiments for Bitcoin using fine-tuned ML models. Extracted sentiments are utilized to compute time lag difference of the impact of news on Bitcoin price. News sentiments further supplement the forecasting of Bitcoin price.

Modules:

- Cloud Computing
- Artificial Intelligence with Computer Vision
- Big Data Analytics
- Advanced Software Engineering

BSc Computer Science: FAST National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences Sep 2018 - June 2022

Dissertation: Online Exam Monitoring System Using Deep Learning Creating an online examination system using advanced deep learning techniques to detect malpractices being done by the student using image and pose detection. Along with real time video streaming.

Modules:

- Advanced Programming
- Database Systems
- Artificial Intelligence
- Parallel and Distributed Computing
- Computer Graphics

Work Experience

AWS & DevOps Engineer: Systems Limited

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

- Undertook training sessions on AWS architecture and tools with 93% assessment score.
- Achieving 100% completion rate of assigned tasks and trainings.
- Appointed as trainer for new resources within one month's period.

Game Developer: Mindstorm Studios

Jun 2021 – Sep 2021

- Implemented a 3D Casual mobile game for mobile devices using Unity Engine.
- Successfully played the role of Programmer and secured honourable mention for the game.
- Achieved understanding of Game Engines and 3D Assets within two months' time.

Other experience

Enrolment Support: University of East London

July 2023 – Present

- Supported new enrolment applicants by taking 100+ queries daily.
- Advised students on multiple enquiries such as payments, registration, courses.
- Worked in correlation with other teams such as Fees & Funding, International Advice, and many others to support the students.

Freelance Software Developer: Fiverr + Outsource Projects

Dec 2022 - Present

- Compiled large- and small-scale software solutions incorporating Python, Databases and ML.
- Received great reviews and referrals from clients.
- Offered services to 30 plus International and Domestic clients.

Hobbies & Interests:

Being a Software developer and having to reside on a chair all day, I do like to keep myself active. For which one my hobbies include doing Calisthenics. In my busy routine I always try to take out time for my physical fitness and health. Apart from that playing table tennis is also a source of replenishment. Additionally, also like to watch Anime and play video games in my leisure time.

References available upon request.